Guide to the Claudia Kolker Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Journalism, id164600
  - Freelance Work, id164676
    - “Girl Gets Special ‘Blessing’ for Football Game Prayer”, Los Angeles Times, September 1999; id165037 (Ovsbox 10, Item 28)
    - “Bush Tangled in Funeral Industry Suit”, Los Angeles Times, September 1999; id165038 (Ovsbox 10, Item 29)
    - “Storm Leaves Texas Coast Soggy but Largely Unscathed”, Los Angeles Times, August 1999; id165039 (Ovsbox 10, Item 30)
    - “Hurricane Hits Thinly Populated Texas Coast”, Los Angeles Times, August 1999; id165040 (Ovsbox 10, Item 31)
    - “NAFTA’s Influence Unfolds in Mexican Bus Crash Lawsuit”, Los Angeles Times, August 1999; id165041 (Ovsbox 10, Item 32)
    - “Latino Groups Urge Boycott of Network TV”, Los Angeles Times, July 1999; id165042 (Ovsbox 10, Item 33)
    - “Hate Crimes Against Latinos on Rise, Study Finds”, Los Angeles Times, July 1999; id165043 (Ovsbox 10, Item 34)
    - “NFL Clings to Its California Dreamin’ as Houston Primps and Fumes”, Los Angeles Times, July 1999; id165044 (Ovsbox 10, Item 35)
    - “Suspected Serial Killer Surrenders at Mexico Border”, Los Angeles Times, July 1999; id165045 (Ovsbox 10, Item 36)
    - “Latinos Labor Under Fear of Serial Killer”, Los Angeles Times, July 1999; id165046 (Ovsbox 10, Item 37)
    - “Pilots Told of Bad Weather, NTSB Says”, Los Angeles Times, June 1999; id165047 (Ovsbox 10, Item 38)
    - “Crash Probe Focuses on Landing in Storm”, Los Angeles Times, June 1999; id165048 (Ovsbox 10, Item 39)
    - “Bus Crash in New Orleans Kills 23”, Los Angeles Times, May 1999; id165049 (Ovsbox 10, Item 40)
    - “Leaders Discuss School Violence at Forum”, Los Angeles Times, May 1999; id165050 (Ovsbox 10, Item 41)
    - “School District Sets Standard for Crisis Prevention”, Los Angeles Times, April 1999; id165051 (Ovsbox 10, Item 42)
    - “Houston’s Zany Art Car Parade Comes of Age”, Los Angeles Times, April 1999; id165052 (Ovsbox 10, Item 43)
    - “Texas Offers Hard Lessons on School Accountability”, Los Angeles Times, April 1999; id165053 (Ovsbox 10, Item 44)
    - “Dallas Mayor Gets Credit for Dispersing City’s Cloud of Hate”, Los Angeles Times, April 1999; id165054 (Ovsbox 10, Item 45)
    - “Faith Adds a New Twist to Saga of Atheist O’Hair”, Los Angeles Times, April 1999; id165055 (Ovsbox 10, Item 46)
    - “That’s My Plane, Fellow Pilot Declares”, Los Angeles Times, March 1999; id165056 (Ovsbox 10, Item 47)
    - “Racist Guilty of Murder in Texas Dragging Death”, Los Angeles Times, February 1999; id165057 (Ovsbox 10, Item 48)
    - “Trial Opens in Black Man’s Savage Dragging Death”, Los Angeles Times, February 1999; id165058 (Ovsbox 10, Item 49)
    - “Execution Is Set for Former Teenage Killer, Now 29”, Los Angeles Times, February 1999; id165059 (Ovsbox 10, Item 50)
    - “Prayerful Octuplets’ Mother Goes Home”, Los Angeles Times, December 1998; id165060 (Ovsbox 10, Item 51)
    - “Assault Counts Face Father of Octuplets”, Los Angeles Times, December 1998; id165061 (Ovsbox 10, Item 52)
    - “Helps Pours In for Parents of Octuplets”, Los Angeles Times, December 1998; id165062 (Ovsbox 10, Item 53)
    - “Texas Woman Now the Mother of Octuplets”, Los Angeles Times, December 1998; id165063 (Ovsbox 10, Item 54)
    - “Critics, Fans Find Common Ground”, Los Angeles Times, December 1998; id165064 (Ovsbox 10, Item 55)
    - “As Oil Prices Wane, So Do Prime Rib Orders at Petroleum Club”, Los Angeles Times, December 1998; id165065 (Ovsbox 10, Item 56)
    - “Escaped Death Row Inmate Found Dead”, Los Angeles Times, December 1998; id165066 (Ovsbox 10, Item 57)
    - “Legal Assaults Against States Anti-Sodomy Laws Multiply”, Los Angeles Times, December 1998; id165067 (Ovsbox 10, Item 58)
    - “Ex-Louisiana Gov. Edwards Indicted”, Los Angeles Times, November 1998; id165068 (Ovsbox 10, Item 59)
    - “6 Houston Officers Fired for Role in Fatal Shooting of Man in Raid”, Los Angeles Times, November 1998; id165069 (Ovsbox 10, Item 60)
    - “Four More Bodies Found in Texas Flood Waters”, Los Angeles Times, October 1998; id165070 (Ovsbox 10, Item 61)
    - “U.S. Names Alleged Leader of Drug Cartel”, Los Angeles Times, October 1998; id165071 (Ovsbox 10, Item 62)
    - “Residents Pick Up Pieces Left by Hurricane Georges”, Los Angeles Times, September 1998; id165072 (Ovsbox 10, Item 63)
    - “Georges Hits Mississippi; 1.5 Million Evacuated”, Los Angeles Times, September 1998; id165073 (Ovsbox 10, Item 64)
    - “New Orleans Braces for Georges”, Los Angeles Times, September 1998; id165074 (Ovsbox 10, Item 65)
    - “Hurricane Georges Heads for Gulf Coast”, Los Angeles Times, September 1998; id165075 (Ovsbox 10, Item 66)
    - “Intrigue Swirls Around Missing Mexican Diva”, Los Angeles Times, June 1999; id165076 (Ovsbox 10, Item 67)
    - “Kicking the Gang Attraction: In Gulfton, soccer is much more than a game”, Houston Press, July 1995; id165077 (Ovsbox 10, Item 68)
    - “Stay or Go? Houston’s Salvadorans are given more time to worry”, Houston Press, December 1994; id165078 (Ovsbox 10, Item 69)
    - “Getting the Lead Out: A Mexican folk remedy stymies attempts to cleanse Houston of a heavy metal”, Houston Press, December 1995; id165079 (Ovsbox 10, Item 70)
    - “President Who? A question of office splits a venerable Hispanic organization”, Houston Press, December 1995; id165080 (Ovsbox 10, Item 71)
    - “The Proposition: In Houston, illegal immigrants wait to see what hand California’s Proposition 187 has dealt them”, Houston Press, November 1994; id165081 (Ovsbox 10, Item 72)
    - “Family Feud: As Latino literature moves into the mainstream, the ties that once bound grow frayed”, Houston Press, July 1995; id165082 (Ovsbox 10, Item 73)
    - Rotarian magazine, May 2012; id165083 (Ovsbox 10, Item 74)
    - “The Blood of the Lambs: Members of the Voice of the Martyrs Sneak Into Perilous Regions to Aid Persecuted Christians. Not That They Want the Suffering to End”, Los Angeles Times, March 2004; id165084 (Ovsbox 10, Item 75)
    - ”Hidden City” Book Review, id165085 (Ovsbox 10, Item 76)
    - “Concepción”, undated; id165086 (Ovsbox 10, Item 77)
    - “Boy’s Joy Ride Aloft Alarms Amazes Pilot”, Los Angeles Times, June 1999; id165087 (Ovsbox 10, Item 78)
    - “Dipping in the Money Pool: An old-world tradition helps immigrants build a new life Houston”, Houston Press, undated; id165088 (Ovsbox 10, Item 79)
    - “We used to live together: Divide widens for Muslims, Hindus in India”, Houston Chronicle, July 2002; id165089 (Ovsbox 10, Item 80)
    - “Tornado Leaves Quite a Paper Trail in Downtown Fort Worth”, Los Angeles Times, April 2000; id165090 (Ovsbox 10, Item 81)
    - “Church’s perpetual vigil is oasis for spiritually needy”, Houston Chronicle, December 1997; id165091 (Ovsbox 10, Item 82)
    - “A beauty of a dispute / Separating fiction, fact, in gossip wars / Slur surrounding surgery lawsuit inflame Vietnamese community”, Houston Chronicle, September 1996; id165092 (Ovsbox 10, Item 83)
    - “Texas candidates debate in Spanish: Latinos hold key in governor race”, Boston Sunday Globe, March 2002; id165093 (Ovsbox 10, Item 84)
    - “In Moscow, a mandate to be merry: Mayor decrees businesses must decorate for the holidays—or pay a fine”, Houston Chronicle, December 2002; id165094 (Ovsbox 10, Item 85)
    - “Russian female drivers get no respect”, St. Petersburg Times, February 2003; id165095 (Ovsbox 10, Item 86)
    - “The Goddess Needs a Home: Vietnamese Shrine Forced to Move Soon from Midtown Area”, Houston Chronicle, April 2003; id165096 (Ovsbox 10, Item 87)
    - “Texas Takes California Title as State With the Most Behind Bars”, Los Angeles Times, October 2000; id165097 (Ovsbox 10, Item 88)
    - “U.S. Charges Alleged Drug Cartel Leader in 10 Deaths”, Los Angeles Times, September 2000; id165098 (Ovsbox 10, Item 89)
    - “Galveston’s Great Storm: Glitz to Horror in Hours”, Los Angeles Times, September 2000; id165099 (Ovsbox 10, Item 90)
    - “In Texas, They Shall Not Want for Pregame Prayer”, Los Angeles Times, September 2000; id165100 (Ovsbox 10, Item 91)
    - “Unabashed Texas Town Takes Issue with Its Bad Reputation”, Los Angeles Times, August 2000; id165101 (Ovsbox 10, Item 92)
    - “Texas Executes Convicted Murderer in Case Surrounded by Controversy”, Los Angeles Times, June 2000; id165102 (Ovsbox 10, Item 93)
    - “A Roiling Debate on Texas Executions”, Los Angeles Times, June 2000; id165103 (Ovsbox 10, Item 94)
    - “Bush Says He Might Delay Execution for DNA Tests”, Los Angeles Times, June 2000; id165104 (Ovsbox 10, Item 95)
    - “Chronic Flaws Blamed for Fall of Texas Bonfire Pile”, Los Angeles Times, May 2000; id165105 (Ovsbox 10, Item 96)
    - “Deadly Siege Simulation Filmed”, Los Angeles Times, March 2000; id165106 (Ovsbox 10, Item 97)
    - “Bush’s Absence Doesn’t Hinder Texas Operations”, Los Angeles Times, March 2000; id165107 (Ovsbox 10, Item 98)
    - “On Killing and Justice”, Los Angeles Times, February 2000; id165108 (Ovsbox 10, Item 99)
    - “Bush’s Texas Traits Don’t Rope In All”, Los Angeles Times, February 2000; id165109 (Ovsbox 10, Item 100)
    - “Pakistanis bitter alliance hasn’t reduced poverty”, Houston Chronicle, undated; id165110 (Ovsbox 10, Item 101)
    - “’Possessed’ women flock to Indian Shrine for healing from mental illness”, Houston Chronicle, September 2002; id165111 (Ovsbox 10, Item 102)
    - “Rare Volume documents black achievement in 1915”, Houston Chronicle, February 1997; id165112 (Ovsbox 10, Item 103)
    - “Break from burial tradition spurs uproar: Wife didn’t send spouse’s body home from internment”, Houston Chronicle, March 1998; id165113 (Ovsbox 10, Item 104)
    - “India’s citizens worry little about Armageddon: Nation that’s never entered nuclear war can’t imagine one”, Houston Chronicle, June 2002; id165114 (Ovsbox 10, Item 105)
    - “The Salty Lagoon”, Texas Parks and Wildlife, July 2003; id165115 (Ovsbox 10, Item 106)
    - “Hidden Houston: The City You See On the Surface Is Not All the City There Is”, Cite: The Architecture and Design Review of Houston, March 2001; id165116 (Ovsbox 10, Item 107)
    - “Device lets amputees stand tall”, St. Petersburg Times, December 2002; id165117 (Ovsbox 10, Item 108)
    - “Enron workers’ loss more than fiscal”, Boston Sunday Globe, January 2002; id165118 (Ovsbox 10, Item 109)
    - “Mother guilty in deaths of 5 children”, The Boston Globe, March 2002; id165119 (Ovsbox 10, Item 110)
    - “Yates gets life sentence for slayings: Verdict fuels debate on laws, psychosis”, The Boston Globe, March 2002; id165120 (Ovsbox 10, Item 111)
    - “A new market for crown jewels: Texas firm makes hay by pitching Stetsons at Latino immigrants”, The Boston Globe, August 2001; id165121 (Ovsbox 10, Item 112)
    - “India’s citizens worry little about Armageddon: Nation that’s never entered nuclear war can’t imagine one”, Houston Chronicle, June 2002; id165122 (Ovsbox 10, Item 113)
    - “Indian-Pakistani tensions easing: Kashmir selling continues amid gestures; 10 killed”, Houston Chronicle, undated; id165123 (Ovsbox 10, Item 114)
- Miscellaneous Papers and Journals, id164601
  This series contains miscellaneous materials such as Claudia’s journals, personal calendars, and other miscellanea.
  - Personal Journals, id165124
    - Journals, 07-08, 2007-2008; id165128 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 09, 2009; id165129 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Journals 10-11, 2010-2011; id165130 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Journals, undated; id165131 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Calendars, id165125
    - Calendars, 2009-2011; id165133 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Miscellanea, id165126
    - Correspondence, 1987-2006; id165135 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Certificates and Awards, 1999-2004; id165136 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Hasta no verté Jesús mío/Here;s to You, Jesusa!, 1991-2002; id165137 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Tapes, 2001; id165138 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Claudia's CV/Resume, undated; id165139 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Photos, undated; id165140 (Box 7, Folder 14)